maturetimes.co.uk 2019-08-29

# Privacy & Cookie Policy | Mature Times | Deals, Offers, Articles On Health, Travel, Property

Highwood House Publishing Limited (HHPL) is a company registered in England and Wales under company registration number 05112696 and the registered office is located at 6, Railway Wharf, Station Road, Wrington, Bristol, BS40 5LL.

HHPL is committed to protecting the privacy of users of the site www.maturetimes.co.uk at all times. It is our policy to disclose within this statement all issues related to privacy in the collection by HHPL of personally identifiable information from the users of the site www.maturetimes.co.uk.

Our Privacy Policy is written to advise you of our practices with regards to the collection, management, use and disclosure of information that you may provide via the website www.maturetimes.co.uk. Whenever you use our site you consent to the collection, use and disclosure of that information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. From time to time, we may make changes and adjustments to our policy and the operational processes that it describes. You can find the date that this policy was last revised at the bottom of the document. Where there is a significant change we will notify you so that you can decide whether you wish to continue to receive communications from us.

### How we use personal information

HHPL is a data controller in respect of all information we collect and receive about you when you use our services. We have put in place a set of information guidelines that serve as the basis for our customer and advertiser relationships. These guidelines have been developed to comply with the Data Protection Act 1998 and the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003. We will also, from time to time, act on advice published by the Information Commissioner.

Highwood House Publishing Limited is registered as required under the Data Protection Act 1998, registration number Z960527X. If you require information on the Data Protection Act 1998, the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003 or the Information Commissioner you can visit www.dataprotection.gov.uk.

The following measures are taken by HHPL to protect our users’ privacy:-

  * We do not provide or sell your details to advertisers or third parties. In the case of any offers made to you these offers will only come from HHPL.
  * HHPL and our group of companies may contact you by post or telephone with details of their products, services and promotions. In the case of e-mail this correspondence will be sent to all users excepting those who have specifically opted out of receiving communications via these methods.
  * All e-mail correspondence that you receive will include an unsubscribe option.
  * We reserve the right to disclose information about member usage and demographics to advertisers and partners, but this will only be in anonymous aggregate format. HHPL will not reveal your personal identity in connection with the disclosure of such information.

### What Personally Identifiable Information Is Collected About You?

Information is collected on our users in two ways: through the use of cookies and through registration. For more information about cookies please see below.

We may require users to provide us with a name, e-mail address, postal address, postcode, gender and date of birth in order to register for access to certain services. We may also ask for other non-mandatory demographic information from subscribers.

Following registration we will employ a registration cookie to recognise a subscriber and his or her access privileges on www.maturetimes.co.uk as well as to track site usage.

We will also collect personal information from you through your use of enquiry and feedback forms and every time you e-mail us your details. We will only collect such information when you choose to supply it to us.

We will also log IP addresses, or the location of your computer on the internet, for systems administration and troubleshooting purposes. We occasionally use IP addresses to track a user’s session, but do not link IP addresses to personally identifiable information.

For your information, an IP address is a number assigned to your computer by your Internet Service Provider (ISP), so you can access the internet. An IP address is generally considered to be non-personally identifiable information, because in most cases an IP address is dynamic (i.e. it changes each time you connect to the internet), rather than static (i.e. unique to a particular user’s computer).

### What Do We Do With The Information We Collect?

We may use the information we collect to perform statistical analyses of user behaviour in order to measure relative consumer interest in the various areas of our site (to improve our site) and to inform advertisers as to how many consumers have seen their advertising content. In performing these statistical analyses, we will disclose information to third parties only in aggregate form. Personal information on individual subscribers will not be provided to third parties.

Our website also contains links to websites owned and operated by third parties. The third party companies are responsible for ensuring their websites adhere to their own privacy policies, including the use of cookies. We do not take any responsibility or liability for the practices of these third parties.

We may periodically send you e-mail updates on www.maturetimes.co.uk and services offered by www.maturetimes.co.uk and its advertisers. All users will receive these communications via e-mail unless they have specifically opted not to receive these communications. If you wish to opt out of receiving such information from us, then please use the unsubscribe option included in all our e-mail correspondence or send an e-mail to unsubscribe@maturetimes.co.uk stating that you would prefer not to receive such mailings.

We will use files generated by our web servers to analyse site usage and statistics but the files do not identify any personal information. Files analysis helps us to understand usage patterns on our website and to make improvements to our service.

### ‘Third Party’ Advertising Cookies

Most of the advertisements that you will see on www.maturetimes.co.uk are generated by third parties. Some of these third parties will generate their own cookies to track how many people have seen a particular advertisement (or use the services of third parties to do this), and to track how many people have seen it more than once. These cookies cannot be used to identify an individual; they can only be used for statistical purposes, for example, in providing you with advertisements that are more relevant to your interests. Some of the information gleaned from third party cookies will be aggregated with other anonymous information for statistical purposes. The third party companies that generate these cookies have their own, very strict, privacy policies but we don’t have access to these cookies; other than allowing them to be served, we have no role to play in these cookies at all (although we may use statistical information arising from these third party cookies and provided to us by third parties, to improve the targeting of advertisements to users of www.maturetimes.co.uk.

If you would like to disable these ‘third party’ cookies generated by advertisers or providers of targeted advertising services, you can turn them off by going to the third party’s website and getting them to generate a one-time “no-thanks” cookie that will stop any further cookies being served to your machine.

### With Whom Do We Share The Information We Collect?

We do not sell your personal information to others. However, in the legitimate course of our business we may be asked to provide aggregate statistics on our customers, sales, traffic patterns and related site information to reputable third-party vendors. However, any information so provided will include no personally identifying information.

### The Option to Opt Out

We use legitimate business interest as the legal basis for communications with you by email. Each email communication that you receive from us will provide you with an option to unsubscribe or you can use the contact details at the end of this policy to tell us you would like to opt out.

### Other processing activities

We also process personal data in the following ways that are within our legitimate business interest:

We may analyse data we hold about you to ensure that the content and timing of communications that we send you are as relevant to you as possible.

We may use profiling techniques on the data we hold about you or on rare occasions, employ third party insight companies to provide us with information about you that will help us to communicate in a relevant way with you.

In all of the above cases we will always keep your rights and interests at the forefront of our operations. You can object to any of this processing at any time. If you wish to do this, please use the contact details at the end of this policy.

### Your debit and credit card information

Please note that our website is a newspaper website and not a retail website. Therefore, you will never be asked to buy products and services direct from the website and you will therefore never be asked to provide personal debit or credit card information whilst using our website.

### Sensitive personal data

Data Protection law recognises that certain categories of personal information are more sensitive than others such as health information, race, religious beliefs and political opinions. We do not collect this type of information about our visitors unless there is a clear reason for doing so (and is collected with explicit consent).

### Security of your personal information

We put in place appropriate safeguards (both in terms of our procedures and the technology we use) to keep your personal information as secure as possible. We will ensure that any third parties we use for processing your personal information, for example our mailing house, do the same. Your data is kept securely separate from the website, and the website is HTTP Secure (HTTPS).

We will not transfer, process or store your data anywhere that is outside of the European Economic Area.

### Your rights to your personal information

You have a right to request a copy of the personal information that we hold about you at any time. You have the right to request that any inaccuracies in this data is corrected. You have the right to stipulate that all records about you are deleted. Please use the contact details at the end of this policy if you would like to exercise your right to do this.

If you no longer wish us to use your data, or wish to amend the type of communications you receive, then you can opt out of our communications at any time via the ‘unsubscribe’ link included in every email.

### Third parties

There are certain circumstances under which we may disclose your personal information to third parties. These are as follows:

To our service providers who process data on our behalf and on our instructions (for example our mailing house which broadcasts our newsletters). In these cases we require that these third parties comply with data protection laws and our instructions, including the secure disposal of records after processing is completed.

Where we are under a duty to disclose your personal information in order to comply with any legal obligation (for example to government bodies and law enforcement agencies).

### Contact details and further information

Please get in touch with us if you have any questions about any aspect of this Notice, or if you would like to request further information about, or object to, any aspect of processing of your personal data described above.

This Policy last updated on the 24 May 2018.
